# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello everyone, I'm Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
In this video, I'll share the recipe of an everyday dish
# 泡椒腰花
Pork Kidney with Pickled Chili
# 首先我们准备猪腰1对
First, we prepare a pair of pork kidneys
# 从中间片开之后再小心翼翼地去除腰骚
Slice it open in the middle and carefully remove the extra parts
# 一般来说菜刀越薄越好切
The thinner your knife is, the easier it is to cut it
# 去除腰骚之后下一步开始改刀
After removing the extra parts, start cutting it
# 这里跟大家分享一个最简单的切法
Now I'll share the easiest way to do it
# 首先我们将腰花竖着切进三分之二
First we cut through 2/3 of it
# 每一刀之间间隔3毫米即可
And make sure there's 3mm between each cut
# 同学们切记不要切断
Make sure don't cut it all the way through
# 然后转过来横着以同样的方式切进三分之二
Then turn it arround and cut through 2/3 in the same way
# 再切到第二刀的时候切断
At the second cut, cut it through
# 猪腰切好之后下一步放入碗中
After we're done cutting, put it in the bowl
# 再加入适量的清水清洗几遍去除血水和骚味
Add some water to rinse it several times to remove the blood and the smell
# 清洗干净之后捞出挤干水分下一步开始腌制
After cleansing, get rid of the water and start marinating
# 首先我们在碗中加入少许的食用盐（约0.3克）
First we add some salt to the bowl (around 0.3g)
# 加入一小半勺胡椒粉
Add half a teaspoon of ground pepper
# 加入料酒2克
Add 2g of Chinese cooking wine
# 加入生抽酱油2克
Add 2g of light soy sauce
# 加入少许的老抽调色
Add some dark soy sauce for the color
# 最后加入几勺干淀粉搅拌均匀
Finally add a few teaspoons of starch and mix it
# 同学们料汁最好调成略微干一些
It'll be the best if the marinade is not too diluted
# 这样能防止脱浆
So that it doesn't come off
# 然后加入洗干净的腰花轻轻的搅拌均匀备用
Then add the cleaned pork kidneys and gently stir
# 同学们切记下手别太重防止把腰花抓烂
Remember to be gentle or the pork kidneys would fall apart
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Now let's prepare the minor ingredients
# 准备红泡椒30克切碎备用
Prepare 30g of red pickled chili and mince them
# 准备大蒜15克拍散之后切碎备用
Prepare 15g of garlic and mince it
# 准备生姜1小块剁碎备用
Prepare a small piece of ginger and mince it
# 准备大葱几根从中间破开之后切碎备用
Prepare a few green onions, slice it in the middle, and mince it
# 最后准备适量的藿香叶切碎备用
Finally prepare some Huoxiang leaves and mince it
# 没有藿香的同学可以根据个人口味用香菜或者紫苏代替
If you don't have it, you can use cilantro or Perilla
# 下一步开始制作
Next start making the dish
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First we heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的底油（35克左右）
After it's heated, add some base oil (35g)
# 油温烧至5成热之后将腌制好的腰花下锅滑散
When it's 150 degrees, add the marinated pork kidneys
# 同学们腰花下锅之前最好先再次拌匀
It's the best to mix them again beforehand
# 腰花滑散之后加入切好的辅料爆香（生姜，大蒜，泡椒）
After they're no longer sticking together, add the minor ingredients to stir fry together (ginger, garlic, pickled chili)
# 中途加入红油豆瓣酱3克
Add 3g of chili oil doubanjiang
# 豆瓣酱炒香之后再加入生抽酱油3克从锅边淋入
After you start to smell it, add 3g of light soy sauce from the side
# 然后开始调味
Then start seasoning
# 锅中加入鸡精1克
Add 1g of Chicken bouillon powder to the wok
# 加入少许白糖
Add some sugar
# 调好味之后加入适量的水淀粉离火勾芡
After seasoning, add some water starch and remove the wok from the stove
# 再加入切好的大葱翻炒几下
Add minced green onions and mix it
# 最后加入切好藿香叶翻炒均匀即可出锅装盘
Finally add the cutted Huoxiang leaves and mix it properly. Now it's ready
# 一道非常美味的泡椒腰花就制作完成
We've made a very delicious dish: Pork Kidney with Pickled Chili
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，为了保证腰花不被抓烂，必须先把调料拌匀化开再搅拌
# 第二，小煎小炒一锅成菜属于自贡着名炒法，底油可以适量的大一些
# 第三，没有藿香的同学可以用香菜，芹菜叶，或者紫苏代替
# 泡椒猪腰的技术总结完毕
Now let's summarize the key techniques
First, to make sure the pork kidney doesn't fall apart in the marinade, make sure we mix the marinade properly
Secondly, mildly stir-frying in one wok is a famous technique in Zigong, and we can add slightly more base oil
Thirdly, if you don't have Huoxiang leaves, you can use cilantro, celery, or Perilla
Above is all techniques for Pork Kidney with Pickled Chili